

Software:

InDesign Illustrator Photoshop Acrobat Microsoft Office SketchUp

Other:

Problem solving Time management Processes Highly organised Eye for detail Good communicator Work well autonomously and within teams

Education:

2003

Hirt & Carter, Durban Desktop Publishing Certificate (Completed with 86% overall mark)

1999 - 2001

Varsity College / University of South Africa, Durban Bachelor of Arts in Psychology and Communications (Incomplete)

1994 - 1998

Westville Boys' High School

Languages:

English.

References available on request.

Richard Martin Operator, Layout & Finished Artist Phone: 0439 001 452 Email: richard.martin001@gmail.com

Contact

About:

The bulk of my experience has been working for in-house agencies at major retail brands doing layout of adverts, product catalogues and packaging. I've spent the last few years working predominantly in foods packaging for one of the biggest retail brands in South Africa, but my experience also includes all aspects of below-the-line advertising and branding. From exhibition stands to business cards I have produced finished art for it all! I strive to innovate and streamline processes within my skill set and am a guick learner. I go above and beyond to add value to any team I lead or am a member of.

Work Experience:

2021 | Freelance DTP Operator & Finishing Artist, Cape Town -Contracted to Woolworths Pty Ltd.

- vished artwork on foods packaging.
- Contracted to do layout and fireResponsibilities included layout layout of packaging conforming to legislation retouching ckaging, adhering to corporate identity specifications, of images used on endments and checking of proofs and contract proofs. dieline develoome

2014 - 2020 | Woolwork

- Layout and finished artwork on
- Layout and finished artwork on look packaging.
 Responsibilities included ayout of packaging conforming to legislation, retouching of images used on packacing, adhering to corporate identity specifications, dieline development and amendments and checking of proofs and contract proofs.

2012 - 2014 | Freelance DTP Operator & Finishing Artist, Cape Town -Contracted to Woolworths Pty Ltd

- Contracted to do layout and finished artwork on foods packaging.
- Responsibilities included layout of packaging conforming to legislation, retouching of images used on packaging, adhering to corporate identity specifications, dieline development and amendments and checking of proofs and contract proofs.

2008 - 2012 | Redwood Design, Cape Town - Production Manager / DTP Operator

- Layout and finished art for various corporate identity elements.
- Layout and finished art for various brochures and corporate documentation.
- Layout, specification and finished art for various exhibition stands and event branding.
- Product photography and retouching for online and print media.
- Brands worked on included Green Building Council of South Africa, Rogz Pragma Absa Ca

Advertising & Design, Johannesburg - DTP Operator

- des for various retail brands (dumbo Cash & Carry, e, Kayo Cash & Carry). - Layout of product catal Reliable Music Warel
- Layout and finished art for documents, instore signage, promotional material and corporate identifi
- and retouching for various product catalogues, print adverts - Product photograp and websites.

2003 - 2004 | Mass Discounters, Durban - Junior DTP Operator

- Layout of newspaper and broadsheet adverts for Game and Dion stores.